<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<cookbook version="1">

    <recipe>
		<title>Meatballs</title>
		<preptime>25 min</preptime>
		<cooktime>1 h</cooktime>
		<servings>6</servings>
		<description>
			<li>
				The Best Swedish Meatballs are smothered in the most amazing rich and creamy gravy. 
				The meatballs are packed with such delicious flavor you will agree these are the BEST you have ever had!
			</li>
		</description>
		<ingredient>
			<li>
				1 pound ground beef
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac14; cup panko bread crumbs
			</li>
			<li>
				1 tablespoon parsley, chopped
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac14; teaspoon ground allspice
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac14; teaspoon ground nutmeg
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac14; cup onion, finely chopped
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac12; teaspoon Garlic Powder
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac12; teaspoon Pepper
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac12; teaspoon salt
			</li>
			<li>
				1 egg
			</li>
			<li>
				1 tbsp. olive oil
			</li>
			<li>
				5 tbsp. butter
			</li>
			<li>
				3 tbsp. flour
			</li>
			<li>
				2 cups beef broth
			</li>
			<li>
				1 cup heavy cream
			</li>
			<li>
				1 Tablespoon Worcestershire sauce
			</li>
			<li>
				1 tsp. Dijon mustard
			</li>
			<li>
				salt and pepper to taste
			</li>
		</ingredient>
		<recipetext>
			<li>
				In a medium sized bowl combine ground beef, panko, parsley, allspice, nutmeg, onion, garlic powder, pepper, salt and egg. Mix until combined.
			</li>
			<li>
				Roll into 12 large meatballs or 20 small meatballs. In a large skillet heat olive oil and 1 Tablespoon butter. 
				Add the meatballs and cook turning continuously until brown on each side and cooked throughout. Transfer to a plate and cover with foil.
			</li>
			<li>
				Add 4 Tablespoons butter and flour to skillet and whisk until it turns brown. Slowly stir in beef broth and heavy cream. 
				Add worchestershire sauce and dijon mustard and bring to a simmer until sauce starts to thicken. Salt and pepper to taste.
			</li>
			<li>
				Add the meatballs back to the skillet and simmer for another 1-2 minutes. Serve over egg noodles or rice.
			</li>
		</recipetext>
		<imagepath>/images/meatballs.png</imagepath>
	</recipe>
		
	<recipe>
		<title>Pancakes</title>
		<preptime>25 min</preptime>
		<cooktime>1 h</cooktime>
		<servings>12</servings>
		<description>
			<li>
				Maple Sweet Potato Pancakes. These maple sweetened sweet potato pancakes are so thick and fluffy. Not to mention perfectly spiced and flavorful. 
			</li>
		</description>
		<ingredient>
			<li>
				1 and &amp;frac14; cup sweet potato puree 
			</li>
			<li>
				1 5.3 ounce container greek yogurt
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac12; cup milk
			</li>
			<li>
				3 tablespoons unsalted butter melted
			</li>
			<li>
				1 large egg
			</li>
			<li>
				2 tablespoons maple syrup
			</li>
			<li>
				1 cup all purpose flour
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac14; teaspoon baking powder
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac14; teaspoon baking soda
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac12; teaspoon salt
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac12; teaspoon ground nutmeg
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac14; teaspoon ground cinnamon
			</li>
			<li>
				&amp;frac12; teaspoon vanilla extract
			</li>
		</ingredient>
		<recipetext>
			<li>
				In a large mixing bowl combine the sweet potato puree and greek yogurt. Add in the milk, melted butter, egg and maple syrup. Stir to combine.
			</li>
			<li>
				Add in the flour, baking powder, baking soda, salt, nutmeg and cinnamon to the mixing bowl. Stir to combine. Add in the vanilla extract and mix.
			</li>
			<li>
				Heat a large skillet over medium heat. Spray with cooking spray or melt some butter on the pan. 
				Using a &amp;frac14; measuring cup scoop the pancake batter and pour onto the heated skillet. Work in batches of 3-4 pancakes depending on what can fit on the skillet.
			</li>
			<li>
				Cook the pancakes for about 2-3 minutes, you will notice bubbles forming on the top of the pancake batter, then flip to cook the other side for an additional 2-3 minutes. 
				Remove the pancakes from the skillet and continue until all pancake batter is cooked.
			</li>
			<li>
				Serve warm with butter and additional maple syrup. Enjoy!
			</li>
		</recipetext>
		<imagepath>/images/pancakes.jpg</imagepath>
	</recipe>
	
</cookbook>